Tyler T. Mullen

Email: T_mullen93@yahoo.com | Phone: 612-644-7902 | Address: 8916 Northwood Parkway, New Hope, MN 55427

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-mullen-94905553/ GitHub: https://github.com/RatofWrath

Website: https://ratofwrath.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Web developer with a bachelor's degree in computer science as well as experience coding sorting algorithms and a compiler for mini-pascal using Java. Currently enrolled in a boot camp for full stack development with MERN. Experienced in teaching end-users how to use technologies and working in fast-paced environments with demanding deadlines that require communication with co-workers and clients. Looking forward to utilizing my expertise in coding and troubleshooting to create web pages, applications and software.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient with Java, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, Firebase, phpMyAdmin, API's and Git Bash.

PROJECTS

LIRI Search Bot | https://github.com/RatofWrath/liri-node-app

- Allows the user to run searches for concert dates, movie information, and song information
- Uses Spotify's API to search Spotify's database and Axios to search Bands-in-town and OMDB's database
- Node.js, Moment, Spotify API, Axios, JavaScript

Train Scheduler https://github.com/RatofWrath/Train-Scheduler https://ratofwrath.github.io/Train-Scheduler/

- Adds trains to a schedule, displaying name, destination, and next arrival.
- Sends data to, and pull data from, firebase to display all scheduled trains.
- Firebase, Moment, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Gridiron Greats Trivia Game | https://github.com/RatofWrath/TriviaGame | https://ratofwrath.github.io/TriviaGame/

- Six question football trivia game that the user has ninety seconds to complete.
- Upon completion, screen displays the number of correct, incorrect, and unanswered questions
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Crystal Collectors Game https://github.com/RatofWrath/unit-4-game/
https://ratofwrath.github.io/unit-4-game/

- Game where user tries to a match target number by clicking on crystals with a hidden number value.
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML

EXPERIENCE

Back of House Team Member - Chick-Fil-A - Bloomington, MN

2017 - Present

- Cultivating strong relationships with co-workers and demonstrating a calm composure during busy and stressful periods
- Oversee food safety by monitoring temperatures and sanitary procedures
- First team member (out of 35) to complete a rigorous online training program set up by franchise operator.
- Train co-workers on proper cleaning and maintenance of deep fryers

<u>Technical Consultant</u> – Allina Health – Minneapolis, MN

2016 - 2017

- Assisted approximately fifty Allina Health patients per day by recovering login information, resetting passwords, and changing account information.
- Knowledgeable in Allina Health's Patient Portal and MyChart, and explained features and benefits to patients.
- Created and processed MyChart user login for new patients

<u>Intern</u> – *Lifeworks* – Eagan, MN

June 2016 – August 2016

- Relocated and rewired approximately twenty computers during the facility's reorganization
- Installed Windows 8 updates onto all computers
- Managed the personal login updates for all 150+ staff members across six offices to ensure they would not be affected by a recent security breach
- Effectively communicated with staff and executed the setup of IT equipment

Wait Staff - Sholom Community Alliance - Saint Louis Park, MN

2011 - 2014

- Provided attentive service to senior residents by serving multi-course meals
- Assisted in pre and post-meal preparation and clean-up
- Aided impaired residents with basic meal assistance

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota, St. Paul, MN – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, currently enrolled

Augsburg College, Minneapolis, MN – B.A. In Computer Science, graduated 2016